### Academic Resume of Shanta, Nusrat Jahan

Academic Degree: B.Sc. on Computer Science From American International University-Bangladesh

Citizen: Bangladeshi

Date of Birth: 16/12/1992

Mailing Address: C/O-Md. Abu Jafar, 195/4-A, Shantibagh, Dhaka-1217,

Bangladesh

Contact No: +8801743471942

E-mail: <a href="mailto:shanta.nusratjahan10@gmail.com">shanta.nusratjahan10@gmail.com</a>

# **Career Objectives:**

To be a researcher & achieve a position, where I can prove my excellence by enhancing the scope of achieving organizational vision by contributing my academic knowledge and practical experience.

#### **Research Interests:**

Area of Data analytics & Information Retrieval, Database System & Information System, Information security & privacy issues, Computer Science Education System.

## **Educational Qualifications:**

Name Of The Degree	Department	Name of the Institute	Passing Year	CGPA
Bachelor Of Science	Computer Science	American International University- Bangladesh(AIUB)	2015	3.46 on a scale of 4.00 ( Last 60 credits 3.65 )
Higher Secondary Certificate Examination	Science	Viqarunnisa Noon School, Dhaka, Bangladesh	2010	4.80 on a scale of 5.00
Secondary School Certificate Examination	Science	Viqarunnisa Noon College, Dhaka, Bangladesh	2008	5.00 on a scale of 5.00

# **Employment Summary:**

1. Internship: Standard Chartered Bank (Country Office Bangladesh), Dept: BTPO-(July,2015-October,2015)

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Have been trained on banking data management system & worked on it
- 2. Data analysis on incoming data for multiple projects.
- 3. Have experience about how their management system running.
- 2. Job: A prominent local software company SmartWebSource (collaborating with a Canadian Software Company)- working on Information System Construct, manage & Data analysis (from January, 2016- June, 2017)

#### Responsibilities:

- 1. Have worked for different projects to create how their database system can be build up
- 2. Have made diagram how the system is going to be built up
- 3. Have figured out the security issues of particular system
- 4. Have made how to reduce related costs
- 5. Interpret data, analyze results provide ongoing reports
- 6. Have collected, organized, analyzed, and disseminate significant amounts of information with attention

### **Undergraduate Thesis Topic:**

"Automated collaborative filtering in World Wide Web Advertising"

B.Sc. in Computer Science Thesis Work (2014-2015)

Supervisor: Former Assistant Professor Debajyoti Karmaker

#### **Overview:**

The thesis focused on how to find out an effective method for web advertising. To find out the method that can make online advertising more effective from the perspective of both the advertisers & users. Using data analytics, data model design, information clustering techniques we have worked on two factors- 1. Targeting consumer behave, 2. Filtering their approach, base on these two factors we have designed data algorithm in which it has been shown how we can filter data to find out effective advertising structure & along with. Using target marketing, we have worked on how interactions are done between the advisers & users. Target advertising makes a minimization of wastage advertising.

### **Undergraduate Projects:**

- Using Java, HTML, CSS, PHP and Mysql:
  - 1. Chemical Firm Management System.
  - 2. Staff time scheduling system for a restaurant.

.

- Using Database design (Oracle, C#) & SQL:
  - 1. Prison Management system
- Operating System: Linux ( Ubuntu):
  - 1. Cyber Café Management System
- Computer Organization & Architecture :
  - 1. Library management System
- Design Prototype (HCI):
  - 1. Smart Remote controller.
  - 2. Touch Screen Key Board Layout
- Management Information System (MIS): Information System Design For a Daily newspaper
   (How their network & database system construct & manage)

• Education System design based on STEM: "How Computer Science Education system functions among the students of High schools & 1<sup>st</sup> year undergraduate student" arranged by Bangladesh Computer Society

#### **Technical Skills:**

Languages: C++, Java, Python, Basic idea about "R"

Development Tools, Methodologies & Environments: Object-Oriented Analysis & Design

(OOAD), Net Beans, Microsoft Visual Studio

**Systems:** Windows, Linux **Databases:** Oracle, SQL

## Workshop & Training attended:

Training:

- 1. Database- Oracle 10g (building Information System & Design) in Grameen Star IT-2015
- 2. Graphics Design- Grameen Star IT-2014
- 3. Digital marketing- MLab-2016

Workshops:

- 1. Information System Design by AIUB-2014
- 2. Have attended workshop on Human Computer Interaction- designing prototype-2015

Graduate Record Exam: AWA: 3.5, Quantitative: 152, Verbal: 148

Linguistic Skills: IELTS: Overall- 6.5 (Reading: 7.5, Writing: 6, Listening: 7, Speaking: 6)

#### **References:**

1. Dr. Dip Nandi

Head of Undergraduate, Department of Computer Science & Engineering American International University-Bangladesh

E-mail: dip.nandi@aiub.edu

2. Md. Saef Ullah Miah

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science & Engineering American International University-Bangladesh

E-mail: saef@aiub.edu